Guide to the Cornell University banners, clothing, and other textiles, 1875-1955.
Cornell University banners, clothing, and other textiles
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University banners, clothing, and other textiles, 1875-1955.
47-7-3439
Cornell University.
48 items.
Memorabilia.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Banners, pennants, pillows, runners, and other cloth items.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Banners, pennants, pillows, runners, jackets, blazers, reunion items, graduation robes and regalia and other cloth items including a Cornell University doctoral hood, originally owned by Dr. William J. Edens, Ph.D. 1937 and Class of 1941 blazer owned by Arthur Townsend Klinger.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University -- Insignia.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See Stephen J. Roberts Papers, #24-2-2903, for an additional banner.
See also Cigarette silk collection, #6612, for additional Cornell University related textiles.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Banners, Pennants, and Flags
  - Banner – "When Better Women are Made Cornell Men Will Make Them", ca. 1956; MU-1211 (Box 1)
  - Large Cornell flag, probably owned by John Sherwood Hoffmire, Class of 1916, 1916; MU-2115 (Box 2)
  - Small banner - "Baker Court, Souvenir of Ithaca", undated; MU-1345 (Box MU 29)
  - Cornell banners, n.d.; MU-1197 & 1198 (Mapcase-folder 2)
  - Cornell banner, MU-1330 (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Silk and felt 1944 square banner, 1944; MU-1329 (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Cornell banners, 1918, n.d.; MU-1358 & 1359 (Mapcase-folder 4)
  - Cayuga Club Banner, a club that later became a chapter of the Sigma Phi Sigma Fraternity, n.d.; MU-1297 (Mapcase-folder 6)
  - Red banner with white “‘84”, class of 1884, 1884; MU-535 (Mapcase-folder 9)
  - Banner, n.d.; MU-1023 (Mapcase-folder 9)
  - Cornell banner, red with white lettering, MU-940 (Mapcase-folder 11)
  - Cornell banner with "Cornell" written on each end and raised emblem in center, MU-1021 (Mapcase-folder 11)
  - Green banner with "1920s here" in white, 1920-1929; MU-455 (Mapcase-folder 12)
  - Cornell 1942 class banner, 1942; MU-2438, MU-1328 (Mapcase-folder 3)
  - Cornell 1944 class banner, 1944; MU-2439-2440 (Mapcase-folder 13)
    Two identical banners, but MU-2439 has a CU button and football pin in the center
  - Cornell pennants, n.d.; MU-1078 and 1079 (Mapcase-folder 6)
  - Cornell pennant with Gothic lettering, n.d.; MU-434 (Mapcase-folder 7)
    Shown as part of the Sesquicentennial Exhibition
  - Cornell pennant with Gothic lettering, MU-2410 (Mapcase-folder 10)
  - Cornell pennant belonging to Dr. Alexander Powell Hyde, Class of 1945, c. 1945; MU-1458 (Mapcase-folder 8)
  - Cornell pennant, circa 1930s; MU-2441 (Mapcase-folder 8)
  - Cornell pennant with emblem, MU-2393 (Mapcase-folder 9)
  - Cornell pennant, red and white, 1907; MU-435 (Mapcase-folder 9)
  - Cornell pennant, maroon & white, n.d.; MU-1130 (Mapcase-folder 9)
  - Cornell Dairy pennant, 1914-1915; MU-2409 (Mapcase-folder 10)
  - Cornell pennant with printed emblem and letters, MU-2411, MU-2442 (Mapcase-folder 10)
  - Cornell pennant with football player, MU-2412 (Mapcase-folder 10)
  - Cornell pennant, MU-2413 (Mapcase-folder 10)
  - Cornell pennants, MU-2096a, MU-2096b (Mapcase-folder 14)
  - Cornell pennant with emblem and red lettering on white, MU-2443 (Mapcase-folder 14)
  - Class of 1944 pennant, MU-2394 (Mapcase-folder 14)
  - Red banner with "1875" in white, MU-602 (Box 4)
  - Red banner with "1881" in white, MU-600 (Box 4)
  - Red banner with "1883" in white, MU-605 (Box 4)
  - Red banner with "1889" in white, MU-589 (Box 4)
  - White canvas banner with "1893" in red, MU-606 (Box 4)
  - White canvas banner with "1896" in red, MU-607 (Box 5)
  - White canvas banner with "1897" in red, MU-608 (Box 5)
  - White canvas banner with "1901" in red, MU-595 (Box 5)
  - White canvas banner with "1902" in red, MU-601 (Box 6)
  - White canvas banner with "1903" in red, MU-588 (Box 6)
  - White canvas banner with "1904" in red, MU-586 (Box 6)
  - White canvas banner with "1905" in red, MU-609 (Box 5)
  - White canvas banner with "1906" in red, MU-611 (Box 6)
  - White canvas banner with "1907" in red, MU-612 (Box 7)
  - White canvas banner with "1908" in red, MU-604 (Box 7)
  - White canvas banner with "1909" in red, MU-585 (Box 7)
  - White canvas banner with "1910" in red, MU-603 (Box 7)
  - White canvas banner with "1911" in red, MU-598 (Box 8)
  - White canvas banner with "1912" in red, MU-599 (Box 8)
  - White canvas banner with "1920" in red, MU-2444 (Box 8)
  - White canvas banner with "1923" in red, MU-2445 (Box 8)
  - White canvas banner with "1924" in red, MU-2446 (Box 9)
  - White canvas banner with "1925" in red, MU-2447 (Box 9)
  - White canvas banner with "1926" in red, MU-2448 (Box 9)
  - White canvas banner with "1928" in red, MU-2449 (Box 9)
  - Gold banner with "Cornell '95" in blue letters and vice versa, MU-610 (Box 10)
  - Red banner with "Cornell 1923" in white, MU-2450 (Box 10)
  - Red banner with "1929" in gray, MU-2451 (Box 10)
  - Yellow banner with "1926" in white, MU-2452 (Box 11)
  - Blue banner with "1923" in white, MU-2453 (Box 11)
  - Red felt banner with "Cornell" in white, MU-2454 (Box 11)
  - Blue banner with "1911" in white, MU-596 (Box 13)
  - Blue banner with "1911" in white, MU-597 (Box 13)
  - Orange banner with "1906" in white, MU-590 (Box 13)
- Series II: Pillows and Decorative Items
  - Laundry bag given to freshman in 1952, 1952; MU-2056 (Box 11)
  - Patchwork quilt by Dilbert H. Decker, class of 1886, MU-328 (Box 12)
  - Red Wool Felt Pillow with "Cornell" in white, n.d.; MU-1019 (Box 3)
  - Cornell pillow (small), n.d.; MU-1220 (Box MU 66)
  - Cornell blanket/rug (small), n.d.; MU-1221 (Box MU 66)
  - Felt Cornell pillow cover owned by Guy Gundaker, n.d.; MU-1212 (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - 2 pillowcases with red satin trim, embroidered wheel and signatures, c.1897-1901; MU-533 & 534 (Mapcase-folder 5)
    MU-533: Signature of women
    MU-534: Signatures of men with date of graduation
  - Cornell woven blanket, MU-2476 (Box 14)
  - Red and white felt pillow cover, 1912; MU-843 (Mapcase-folder 15)
- Series III: Items of Clothing
  - Armband “CHF” red w/white letters, MU-594 (Box 11)
  - Armband, “‘01”, purple with white letters, MU-591 (Box 11)
  - Armbands with buttons, 1904; MU-1214, MU-1353 (Box MU 29)
  - Shawl, 1934; MU-1215 (Box MU 29)
  - Ph.D. hood owned by William Edens, 1937; MU-1291 (Box MU 71)
  - Cornell blazer, 1938; MU-1213
  - Class of 1941 blazer owned by Arthur Townsend Klinger, 1941; MU-1460
  - Class of 1942 Reunion jacket & cummerbund, 1942; MU-1293
  - Blanchard Livingston Rideout graduation regalia, Undated; MU-2718
    Includes two robes one with Cornell seal embroidered on a field of blue, hoods, and mortar boards. One cap has initials BLR inside. Some of these items were worn while Rideout led President Frank Rhodes' 1977 inauguration procession.
  - Seal and Serpent hat, 1905; MU-1257
  - Straw hat with "Cornell '60" written on ribbon, 1960; MU-2455
  - Straw hat with "'40" written on it, 1940; MU-2456
  - Straw hat with "Cornell" written on ribbon, MU-1018
  - Red sesquicentennial scarf created by the Johnson School, 2015; MU-2478 (Box 14)
  - Class of 1957 Freshman Beanie, owned by Carl Schwarz, 1953; MU-2479 (Box 14)
- Series IV: Patches, Badges, and Tags
  - Leather football tag, 1906; MU-1356 (Box 14)
  - Felt badge of Cornell emblem, 1955; MU-2480 (Box 14)